LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
I'm a soldier - that means I'm
Both a defendant and the judge
I am standing on both ends of the flame
Rounding curves
Overtaking life and death,
I run and fight with false shadows
No matter how many threads of
deception are woven together,
The truth shall illuminate
the face of light
Save your tears for the day
When our pain is far behind
On your feet, come with me
We are soldiers stand or die
Save your fears, take your place
Save them for the judgement day
Fast and free, follow me
Time to make the sacrifice.
We rise or fall
Go ahead!
Don't!
Beyond
Paradise
Formation B, eh.
Continue to move through the first floor corridor.
We'll lose them before they gain speed.
Roger.
Wait.
Strange.
The ECM's not working.
Something must have gone wrong.
All men, activate comm systems.
We'll pursue them in Formation A.
Proto. Can you lock the door?
Yes.
Sorry; I'm being an inconvenience.
I don't mind.
More importantly, have there been
any reports from the Tachikomas?
Yes, there were.
The nuclear sub has made no movements.
Also, the patrol plane over
Dejima seems to have crashed.
The refugees shot it down?
I don't know the details, but probably yes.
That means we can make contact with Dejima, no?
That must be it.
Hey!
Don't mind me.
The Chief Cabinet Secretary
told me to come here.
It's a national emergency. Sorry.
Prime Minister, I came to get you.
Chief Aramaki needs your help.
Please come with me.
Understood.
Please take me to him.
Sir, the MSDF's patrol plane
appears to have been shot down.
I see. So he's trying to bring the
isolated refugees together again.
It's about time for the finale.
Take command of the Ministry of Defence and
have them begin shelling from the sea.
Understood.
Is someone there?
Yes, sir.
I'd like you to send out a letter.
A letter, sir?
Yes.
Express delivery.
Tachikoma! Can you hear me?!
We can, Major!
We have confirmed your position!
Batou-San, you're all right!
What happened to Batou and the others?
They're safe.
They seem to be inside a building;
we cannot get visual confirmation.
I found Kuze.
Tell Batou and the others where we are.
Roger.
More importantly, Major, there's big trouble.
What is it?
An Imperial American nuclear submarine
is anchored off the Okinawan coast.
It seems they intend to fire
a nuclear missile at Dejima.
Are you certain?
Give me a visual feed.
Roger.
What?!
Why the hell did we bring this in here?
Goddammit!
What's the inspection team's ETA?
Major!
Batou,
you and the others must immediately
go to the bridge with the plutonium.
They intend to use the nuclear missile
before the inspection team arrives.
Hand the plutonium to the SDF
guarding the bridge at once,
and explain the situation.
You need to get out of there, Major.
We're being tailed by a very
persistent bunch right now.
We'll move as fast as we can,
but we might be cutting it pretty close.
Who are they?
Section 4 Rangers, probably.
You're sure?
Yeah.
I think they came after us
to retrieve the plutonium.
I'll rendezvous with you guys ASAP.
Get away from them, no matter what it takes.
Well, yeah, we'll try.
Let's go!
I believe this is our third,
no, fourth meeting.
Why do you pursue me?
I went through a lot of trouble to get here.
I brought the plutonium as promised.
Come with me.
If you don't, there will be great devastation,
including the deaths of the refugees.
Not to mention, you'll be blamed.
What is going to happen?
A nuclear attack disguised as a
refugee suicide bombing, probably.
What did you say?
Who are you?
Hey, look!
The nuclear sub's hatch has begun to open.
Not good.
The nuclear missile could be fired any minute now.
This is the type that has
a stratospheric trajectory!
It must be to ensure that there
will be no witnesses to the attack.
What?!
Even if they can remove the radiation,
this has enough firepower to kill the
SDF deployed in Nagasaki and Dejima!
So reckless.
Can't we stop the attack somehow?
How about broadcasting this
image to the entire world?
There's no point in that.
Images don't have any value as evidence anymore.
It'd just end up as an entertaining image
that came from an unknown
source at an opportune time.
But, but... if we don't do something...!
Hey! Looks like the Aegis will begin
firing missiles before the nuclear attack!
They caught up to us?
Seems like it.
They must've changed the formation.
Activate thermo-optical camouflage.
Tachikoma, can you find their
encrypted comm system and tap into it?
I'll try.
But please be careful.
There will soon be a missile
attack from the Aegis.
I don't think they'll attack the
residential sectors directly,
but I don't know where the missiles will land.
What about the nuclear missile?
Not yet.
Sounds like it's begun.
We've also got company.
Damn, it's begun.
We don't have time.
Come with me and surrender to the SDF.
I'll take you there by force if necessary.
What is your decision?
Fine by me.
I am explaining the situation to the
refugees who are currently connected to me.
I'll leave the final decision to them,
but for now, let's go to the bridge.
Tachikoma, what are the missiles...
MSDF Air Raid on Dejima!!
It seems the SDF's counterattack has begun
in response to missile attacks from Dejima.
According to the government,
it is an unavoidable measure in order to ensure the
safety of the UN inspection team when they enter Dejima.
It's begun.
Tachikoma, are the Major and the others safe?
Contact with the Major has been cut off.
Batou-San and the others are safe, though.
Is it Section 4 that's chasing them?
Yes.
Sorry for making you wait!
I got so nervous just listening
to the Dejima situation...
What good does it do for you to get nervous?
We'll do what we can, here and now.
Roger.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
The attack seems to have died down for now.
Tachikoma, report.
Major, you're all right!
Yes, barely.
The nuclear missile could be fired at any time.
Please evacuate at once!
Any statements from the government?
There was an announcement that provisional air raids will
be repeated to allow the inspection team to enter, but...
It's no good.
We're trapped.
I see.
Major, are you...
Yes. I'm trapped under a pile of rubble.
It seems I must leave the rest
up to Batou and the others.
Oh no! Can't you get out somehow?
I'll try...
but provide full backup to Batou and the others.
Roger.
Are you connected to the refugees?
Yes. A considerable number have re-linked.
although most of them seem to be
in a panic due to the air raid.
You said there will be a nuclear attack.
How did you hear about it?
Which organisation are you with?
I am with the police.
While investigating the
Individual Eleven's crimes,
we came across a programme within the government
that was designed to eradicate the refugees
and were pursuing you to expose the programme.
Then why did you bring in the plutonium?
Because we knew you didn't get the plutonium.
So, we seized the nuclear
bomb that was used in Fukuoka
in an attempt to resolve the
situation by using it as evidence,
but the enemy's scenario progressed
far more rapidly than we thought.
We didn't think they'd secured a deal
with the Empire for a nuclear strike.
What happened to the plutonium?
My team should be taking it to the SDF,
but that also has become difficult
due to obstruction by a pursuing team.
I see.
Have you given up on making me surrender?
I haven't, but...
I just took down the zoning and
filtering on my hub cyberbrain.
Everyone can connect and
observe what's happening here.
We can attempt to evacuate, but I will also
proceed with my own revolution at the same time.
I became firm in my resolve after
hearing about the nuclear attack.
Resolve?
What do you mean by revolution?
Tachikoma, you haven't tapped
into their comm system yet?
No, they keep randomly changing the
encryption based on prime numbers.
Get down!
Let's relocate.
Understood.
Roger that.
We'll go outside.
Tachikoma, I need that tap!
In a little bit.
Kuze, why did you become the refugees leader?
How did you escape the virus thought
guidance effect in the first place?
I originally had a goal to liberate the refugees.
That resulted in activating
the Individual Eleven virus,
but when I joined the Eleven,
I realised the discrepancy
between their beliefs and mine.
That must be why I could
dissociate myself from the virus.
Why do you want to liberate the refugees, then?
I heard you travelled in Eurasia;
did that have something to do with it?
That... has no direct relation to my decision.
I went on a journey
just because I wanted time to reaffirm my motives
and to see whether I could execute the revolution
or liberation that I envisioned.
What is this "revolution" that you speak of?
The transfer of people to a superstructure.
What this means is that people
should discard their rigid system
and unite with the net.
Unite with the net?
How is the cryptanalysis of the
Section 4 comm system code going?
Mmm, almost there.
I wonder if we could manage
to hack the nuclear sub.
That's impossible.
During an operation,
subs are in standalone status.
What about a crew member's personal email?
If we could tap into a disobedient crew member...
I see.
Worth a shot.
Chief, I brought her.
Proto, open the door.
Prime Minister Kayabuki, I see you are unharmed.
I have been briefed on the situation.
Could you set up a hotline
to the Empire in this room?
I'll try to stop the nuclear attack.
Please do that.
Whether they admit to this
situation is key, however.
That is true.
Don't move!
You are surrounded.
Put the plutonium down and deactivate
your thermo-optical camouflage.
Batou-San! I have a tap!
All right. We'll put it down now!
Hit the walls as soon as I put the case down.
Roger.
What?!
Don't shoot!
Our fields of fire are overlapping!
I'm deactivating my thermo-optical camouflage now.
If you still feel you need to carry out the
mission after I do, go ahead and shoot me.
But if you feel otherwise after seeing my
face, listen to what I say.
It's important.
You...
Your eyes. Are you an ex-Ranger?
That's right.
Due to the incident on the Peninsula,
I began to look at life philosophically.
I found a paradoxical order,
exploitation by the strong,
and corrupt structure.
What disappointed me the most, however,
was the irresponsibility.
The masses don't try to
create anything on their own
and don't understand anything.
And yet, if they find information
convenient to themselves,
they rush to ingest it and
are therefore manipulated.
Without motives, they consume the
infrastructure called the net.
Their actions may bring irresponsible results,
but they feel no responsibility whatsoever.
My revolution is also an act
of revenge against such people.
Revenge?
I've always felt a disparity
between my body and my mind
because I've been a full cyborg since childhood.
I've always wanted to discard
this inconvenient body if I could
and set sail for the sea of the net.
The Asian refugees gave someone
like me a reason to live.
They said that my man-made
face was a very good face
and flattered me by saying my
ghost is expressed within it.
I then realised, for the first time...
that the body and the mind may be indivisible,
and I was able to think of myself as
a human being with a physical body.
However,
even these people went easily
in the direction of convenience
once they encountered palatable information.
It seems human beings were created to descend
to lower heights from the very beginning.
So, how do you propose to enact your revenge?
I will take the memories and ghosts of those
who are connected to me away into the net.
If a nuclear bomb is dropped here,
they will lose their physical bodies,
but they will obtain a
chance to force an evolution.
What is the possibility that they can
retain their individuality on the net?
That, I don't know.
But as pioneers, they can become
entities that will enlighten those
who remained in the infrastructure and make
them continually aware of the superstructure,
in the same way man felt respect and terror
towards spiritual entities in antiquity.
So that's your revenge and salvation
for the ones who disappointed you.
Yes, though I believe it to be a revolution.
You seem to be a full cyborg
from what I've observed.
If so, then you must have
experienced the doubt--the
disparity between the body and
the mind--quite a few times.
Well?
Will you come with me?
Do the refugees intend to go?
Yes.
Unfortunately,
many of them would prefer to execute
the nuclear suicide attack scenario.
I suppose they wish to
believe that they didn't lose,
even though that is an act that
leads them to lower heights.
I see.
Batou,
I'm going to try to save the
refugees with Kuze's method.
You tell the SDF about the nuclear attack.
Do you copy, Batou?
Idiot.
I'm not going to let you go by yourself.
Wait for me!
I'm not going to let you!
What are they waiting for?
No idea.
In any case, let's take this to the bridge.
The GSDF may believe us.
Advance into Dejima as soon as
the second air raid is complete.
We will prepare to accept the inspection team.
Finding out a galaxy
of planets and stars within me.
Listening to each of them
singing the same silent melody.
I've never seen such beauty
in possibility...
No smack of doubt or fear.
(Wake up)
I hear a voice.
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside
(the time is right)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
All I need,
to make all this reality.
(it's inside)
The beauty within the shell.
(deep within the shell)
(within the shell)
(Wake up)
I hear a voice
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
(the time is now)
I see inside,
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
all I need,
to make all this reality,
it's inside
right here within the shell.